# George Kariuki Ngugi

A keen to detail and result driven individual with experience in all sectors in the IT world that include Systems Security, Software production and deployment, Networking, Computer Maintenance etc. My experience from working in an IT intensive environment and studies have seen me grow from a novice when I started out to a person that can be trusted to run computer systems with little or no supervision. I also possess the ability to lead teams and ensure proficiency in duties bestowed on us.

$\bowtie$	ngugigeorge697@gmail.com		0792107437
Q	Nairobi		georgekariuki.tk/
in	linkedin.com/in/george-kariuki-ngugi-709a14148	8	ngugigeorge697@gmail.com
0	github.com/GeorgeKariuki7205		George Ngugi

### **SKILLS**



### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

## Technology Intern. (Co-oprate Security Division)

Safaricom PLC. Waiyaki Way.

05/2019 - 09/2019

Safaricom Is Kenya's Leading Telecommunication and Fin-tech Company.

In Enterprise Risk Management Division (ERM) I was tasked with the following responsibilities:-

- Business Continuity Planning (BCP).
- Business Impact Analysis.
- Service Level Agreement (SLA) formulation, review and analysis.
- Quality Assuarance based on the International Organization for Standardization (ISO) for ISO 27001, ISO 22301, ISO 10002 and IFRS 16 by International Accounting Standards Board (IASB).
- Process Analysis for critical systems such as Oracle ERP, Oracle Business Intelligence, Hyperion accounting, Billing etc.
- Audit Planning, Audit Undertaking, Audit Follow up and reporting.
- Using Ishikawa diagrams and 5 WHYs to come up with root causes for Audit nonconformities and also come up with corrections and corrective actions in audit cases.
- Performing User Acceptability Tests (UAT) and Regression Tests of prerequisite applications before they go live on the internal environment.
- Incidents and crises management.
- Mobile and Web Application Penetration Testing.

## Cyber Assistant

Happy Point Cyber

04/2017 - 09/2017

Happy point Cyber cafe is a one stop shop for all computer related services located in the Busy Nairobi CBD.

The following were the duties that were assigned to

- Setting up the computers for client use.
- Helping Clients on difficulties their facing while using computers
- Maintaining all computers and hardware devices.
- Managing and working with clients.

### **EDUCATION**

# Bsc. Computer Science.

Maseno University.

# Certified Information Communication Technologist (CICT)

KASNEB (Kenya Accountants and Secretaries Examination Board).

12/2017 - Present

Courses

Project: Systematic Project Management.

# **CCNA(Cisco Certified Networking Associate.)**Cisco Academy.

01/2018 - Present

## End User Professional 1 & 2 (EUP 1&2)

Zetech Univeristy.

04/2016 - 08/2016 Distinction

# High school Diploma

St.Josephs High School.

01/2012 – 10/2015

### **PERSONAL PROJECTS**

- 1. Hospital Management system (05/2019 08/2019)
- The project is a system that can be able to manage all facets of the medical filed from patient management, doctor management appointment booking and also medical records management.
- The technologies used in this project include laravel, vue Js Mysql, bootstrap and various Laravel packages such as Laravel PDF, verification, Excel
- GitHub Link: https://github.com/GeorgeKariuki7205/Laravel-Hospital-Management.

#### 2. Asset Management System. (08/2019 – Present)

- This is a system designed for asset management. Its primary roles include the maintenance of a clean record of all the assets that on organisation owns and the recommended breakdown of the growth in asset portfolio.
- The technologies used in this system include Laravel, Vue JS, Ajax, Jquery, Laravel APIs etc as a way of mitigating the needed requirements fir the organisational tesinf and developmnebnt.

### 3. Maseno University Christian Union Website (04/2019 - 06/2019)

- The Christian Union in Maseno University had a problem with the management of their congregation and also passing information within and also without the campus, this lead to the creation of a team that was tasked with the responsibility of coming up with a web based platform to enable individuals pass along information.
- Th GitHub Link to the source code is: https://github.com/GeorgeKariuki7205/Maseno-University-CU.

#### Other Projects.

- $^{\circ}\,$  My other projects can be found in my GitHub and personal website that have been given below.
- Website: georgekariuiki.tk
- GitHub: https://github.com/GeorgeKariuki7205

